Guide to the Albert B. Faust papers, 1919-1945.
Faust, Albert B. papers, 1919-1945
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Albert B. Faust papers, 1919-1945.
14-18-85
Albert Bernhardt Faust, 1870-1951.
9.5 cubic ft.
Clippings, articles, correspondence, manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Recommendations and evaluations for German scholars; clippings, articles, correspondence, original plays, and other papers, mostly on German themes.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Recommendations and evaluations for German scholars; clippings, articles, correspondence, original plays, and other papers, mostly on German themes.
PARTIAL LIST OF CORRESPONDENTS
Joseph Quincy Adams
George Arliss
Karl J. Arndt
Albert W. Aron
G.W. Augerstein
Gerhard Baerg
Frederick Bancroft
Howard F. Barker
Harry Elmer Barnes
Max Baum
Frank Boas
O.L. Bockstahler
A.W. Boesche
Moritz J. Bonn
Horace Brand
Theodore Braun
Wilhelm Braun
Gaius M. Brumbaugh
George Lincoln Burr
A. Busse
T.M. Campbell
Hermann Collitz
George H. Danton
D. Drascher
Clarence Eastman
Ernest Elster
M.B. Evans
Robert Fife
O.S. Fleissner
T.H. Fowler
Katherine Franck
George H. Genzmer
A. Gerber
Gustav Gruener
F.J. Hauptmann
Richard E. Helbig
F.I. Heniott
Harold F. Hippenstiel
Theodore H. Hoffman
O. Holguta
A.R. Hohlfeld
Charles Hull
J. Franklin Jameson
Allen Johnson
E.W. Kermerrer
Albert Kern
James Knauss
Karl F. Koenig
Albert Kresse
H. Kretschmayr
Ernest A. Kubler
W. Kurrelmeyer
J.H.A. Lacher
Martin P. Lampel
Edward A. Leight
Victor F. Lidder
Percy W. Long
Max Monter
R.W. Moore
Henry F. Norden
Gustav Oberlaender
Rudolph Pagenstecher
E. Prokosch
D.R. Roessler
Porter Sargent
Jacob Schiff
Otto Schmidt
Magdalene Schoch
Friedrich Schoenemann
Carl F. Schreiber
Jacob Gould Schurman
Richard Shyrock
E.G. Sihler
Taylor Stark
L.L. Stroebe
Wilbur K. Thomas
Frank Trenler
Curtis C.D. Vail
Ludwig Vogelstein
Camillo von Klenze
M.O. von Klock
Edmund von Mach
B.J. Vos
J.A. Walz
Felix Warburg
Artur Weese
F. Wertheimer
C.B. Wilson
Henry Wood
SUBJECTS
Names:
Faust, Albert Bernhardt, 1870-1951.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Germanic literature--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence
  - 1891-1910 (Box 1)
  - 1910-1913 (Box 2)
  - 1914-1919 (Box 3)
  - 1920-1926 (Box 4)
  - 1926-1927 (Box 5)
  - 1927-1928 (Box 9)
  - 1928-1930 (Box 6)
  - 1930-1931 (Box 7)
  - 1931 (Box 8)
  - 1931-1932 (Box 10)
  - 1932-1934 (Box 11)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 12)
  - 1935-1937 (Box 13)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - 1938-1939 (Box 15)
  - 1939-1941 (Box 16)
  - 1941-1943 (Box 17)
  - 1944-1945 (Box 18)
  - Undated (Box 19)
- News clippings A-R (Box 20)
- News clippings S-Z and Reports A-Z (Box 26)
- German Element newspapers: post-WWI, A-Z (Box 21)
- German Element newspapers: post-WWI, A-Z (Box 22)
- German Element - Schurman Reports, Hindenberg, Von Steuben, Carnegie Peace (Box 23)
- Scrapbook, German Element newspapers, Swiss immigration; Krupp works, miscellaneous items (Box 24)
- World War I pamphlets (Box 25)
- Plays: "The Bank War," "Aaron Burr," "Olsville University" (Box 27)
- Two copies of a typescript titled The German Element in the United States with special reference to its political, moral, social, and educational influence by Albert Bernhardt Faust. Offered in competition for the Conrad Seipp memorial price, March 22, 1907. Each copy is in two parts in bound volumes. Part two gives the subtitle as: with reference to the agricultural and industrial development of the country; with reference to politics, education, culture, social ad ethical standards. The two copies differ slightly. Both copies have some hand written notes, corrections, and marginalia., Msst I 7003